[
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 17 of Solar Storms, Tulik makes a pendant for Aurora out of",
    "a": "the gifted silver earrings",
    "b": "a piece of Agnes's fur coat",
    "c": "a flint stone",
    "d": "Angel's frog in amber",
    "e": "a beaver pelt trimming",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Angel hesitate to use Dora-Rouge's sleeping potion in Chapter 17 of Solar Storms?",
    "a": "The plants used to make it are no longer available.",
    "b": "Agnes had consumed the potion before her death.",
    "c": "Tulik has warned her against it.",
    "d": "She wants to stay awake for Aurora.",
    "e": "Dora-Rouge herself may need it more.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "After being stopped at the roadblock in Chapter 17 of Solar Storms, John Husk and Tommy",
    "a": "try to reach Angel by water but are stopped again",
    "b": "bribe a mail pilot to bring them to town",
    "c": "drive around the roadblock at night",
    "d": "float to Two-Town Post on makeshift rafts",
    "e": "give up and return to Adam's Rib",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following remedies in Solar Storms belongs almost entirely to women?",
    "a": "scilla",
    "b": "wormwood",
    "c": "mikka",
    "d": "redroot",
    "e": "bluestem",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does Angel burn herself in Chapter 17 of Solar Storms?",
    "a": "The flare from a worker's gun lands on her.",
    "b": "Her stress becomes too much to bear.",
    "c": "She falls asleep while tending a sacred fire.",
    "d": "Aurora is in a burning building and she saves her.",
    "e": "A loud sound makes her knock over grease.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why do the electricity poles near Tulik's house start leaning right after their installation?",
    "a": "The installers used wood poles and not metal.",
    "b": "The installers did not track the new flood zone.",
    "c": "The installers measured too much space between poles.",
    "d": "The installers put them in swampy ground.",
    "e": "The installers were not used to permafrost.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 18 of Solar Storms, how does the arrival of electricity change how people clean?",
    "a": "Once-dim places receive much more scrutiny.",
    "b": "Showers are available at all hours of day and night.",
    "c": "Cleaning at night becomes a fad.",
    "d": "Washing machines save labor for women.",
    "e": "Electric floor buffers are in high demand.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Bush set up a space outside Tulik's house in Chapter 18 of Solar Storms?",
    "a": "She offends Tulik.",
    "b": "She is preparing for her arrest.",
    "c": "She is experimenting with plants.",
    "d": "She needs quiet.",
    "e": "She wants to die alone.",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does the arrival of electricity change how Auntie fries chicken?",
    "a": "She uses an electric clock and not her instincts.",
    "b": "She uses two meals' worth of food instead of one.",
    "c": "She uses a hot plate to cook and not a stove.",
    "d": "She uses supermarket chicken and not freshly killed.",
    "e": "She uses packaged spices and not local herbs.",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which heavy metal causes the cancellation of the fishing camp in Chapter 18 of Solar Storms?",
    "a": "cadmium",
    "b": "mercury",
    "c": "thallium",
    "d": "arsenic",
    "e": "lead",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Angel first encounters BEEVCO representatives in",
    "a": "an Anglican church",
    "b": "the Two-Town Post",
    "c": "jail",
    "d": "a protest camp",
    "e": "Tulik's house",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 18 of Solar Storms, the narration compares Auntie's petition to the",
    "a": "Holy Bible",
    "b": "Northwest Treaty",
    "c": "Magna Carta",
    "d": "U.S. Constitution",
    "e": "Declaration of Independence",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "At the first BEEVCO meeting in Solar Storms, Auntie shows her disdain for electricity by",
    "a": "ripping down a wire",
    "b": "turning off a light",
    "c": "smashing a radio",
    "d": "breaking a bulb",
    "e": "tearing out a switch",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Under cover of the first BEEVCO meeting, young activists",
    "a": "dismantle the equipment along the Salt River",
    "b": "sabotage the generator of the power plant",
    "c": "disable the vehicles of the BEEVCO bosses",
    "d": "seize the local BEEVCO offices",
    "e": "destroy the road blocking the whitefish spawning grounds",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why do the BEEVCO bosses stop treating Tulik as an authority?",
    "a": "Tulik is not fluent in English.",
    "b": "Tulik slaps one over an insult.",
    "c": "Tulik weeps for the land in their presence.",
    "d": "Tulik lets Auntie speak freely.",
    "e": "Tulik tends to the infant Aurora.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The first time construction workers harass Tulik’s house, Angel believes it is because they fear",
    "a": "Auntie",
    "b": "Angel herself",
    "c": "Dora-Rouge",
    "d": "Luce",
    "e": "Bush",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who allegedly said, 'We were caesars with no one to answer to'?",
    "a": "Luc de la Corne",
    "b": "Jacques Godin",
    "c": "Daniel Greysolon",
    "d": "Pierre-Esprit Radisson",
    "e": "Medard Chouart",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why do the workers threatening Tulik’s house not want Angel to leave?",
    "a": "They think she might be armed.",
    "b": "They believe she will carry news into town.",
    "c": "They suspect she will sabotage their vehicles.",
    "d": "They see her as a ringleader of resistance.",
    "e": "They are shamed by her youth and femininity.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dora-Rouge compares the sound of workers destroying Tulik’s whalebone fence to",
    "a": "a thunderstorm",
    "b": "Agnes’s death moans",
    "c": "piano keys",
    "d": "the Se Nay River",
    "e": "Wolverine’s fury",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 18 of Solar Storms, Tony apologizes to Loretta by requesting the radio station play",
    "a": "‘It’s the Same Old Song’",
    "b": "‘Baby, Come Back’",
    "c": "‘When a Man Loves a Woman’",
    "d": "‘I Was Wrong’",
    "e": "‘How Am I Supposed to Live Without You’",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Miss Nett first appear in the narrative of Solar Storms?",
    "a": "She comes to shame the workers harassing Tulik.",
    "b": "She hears Angel’s interview on 'Indian Time'.",
    "c": "Her son has joined the protest movement.",
    "d": "She has killed a BEEVCO executive by accident.",
    "e": "Her house has flooded and she is a refugee.",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Miss Nett’s people are the",
    "a": "Megas",
    "b": "Gigas",
    "c": "Nanos",
    "d": "Kilos",
    "e": "Yattas",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 18 of Solar Storms, Dora-Rouge and Miss Nett bond over",
    "a": "cooking",
    "b": "quilting",
    "c": "playing games",
    "d": "making posters",
    "e": "fishing",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 18 of Solar Storms, Bush sets up a darkroom for developing photographs in",
    "a": "Hannah’s shack",
    "b": "Tulik’s basement",
    "c": "the Two-Town Post",
    "d": "an outdoors tent",
    "e": "a church kitchen",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who comes up with the idea of the railroad blockade in Chapter 18 of Solar Storms?",
    "a": "Luce",
    "b": "Miss Nett",
    "c": "Dora-Rouge",
    "d": "Bush",
    "e": "Angel",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Angel associates the first police officers to appear after the railroad blockade with all of the following scents EXCEPT",
    "a": "coffee",
    "b": "cola",
    "c": "tobacco smoke",
    "d": "suntan cream",
    "e": "shaving lotion",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following weapons does Miss Nett take off a young would-be protester in Chapter 18 of Solar Storms?",
    "a": "a rifle",
    "b": "a revolver",
    "c": "a knife",
    "d": "an axe",
    "e": "a crossbow",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chapter 18 of Solar Storms, what does Bush call Arlie Caso House’s followers?",
    "a": "the Apostles",
    "b": "Our Hope",
    "c": "the Quorum of the Twelve",
    "d": "Arlie’s Anchors",
    "e": "Arlie’s Dozen",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which clothing gives the informers away in Chapter 18 of Solar Storms?",
    "a": "trousers",
    "b": "shoes",
    "c": "hats",
    "d": "coats",
    "e": "shirts",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "The crow left at Tulik's house as a warning has been mutilated by",
    "a": "tearing off its beak",
    "b": "breaking its wings",
    "c": "cutting off its feet",
    "d": "sewing its eyes shut",
    "e": "slitting its throat",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  }
]